OLIVER NOLES

GET IN TOUCH

Mobile: 021-040-9840 Portfolio: www.noles.nz Email: oliver@noles.nz github.com/olinoles linkedin.com/in/olivernoles

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an Auckland-based tech enthusiast experienced in software development, web technologies, UI/UX design, and creative projects. I describe myself as a quick learner willing to work with new tools and technologies to achieve project excellence. I enjoy working both independently and in team environments.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Developing full-stack SaaS applications using modern javascript MVC frameworks
- Developing dynamic websites with popular CMS platforms
- Building RESTful API services to OpenAPI standard
- Deploying web applications on serverless and JAMstack architecture
- Working in start-up environments and high performance teams
- · Creating beautiful and functional UI
- Photo & vector editing with Adobe Suite

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- React / Angular / VueJS development using Typescript
- CSS Expert including Tailwind & Bootstrap
- Node JS API development using REST frameworks and serverless architecture.
- SQL and NoSQL architecture and querying.
- PAAS & IAAS with AWS including Lambda functions & S3 services
- · Firebase & real-time data patterns.
- · Code management using Git/Github
- · Docker container image deployment
- Project management and UX storyboarding tools such as Jira, Asana, Figma, and Miro

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

TheMarket NZ | Sep 2021 - Current

- Worked in an agile development team on a large-scale Ecommerce platform.
- Responsible for technical design and development of new features and improvements to themarket.com website, primarily in VueJS & Javascript ES6+.
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs prior to development.
- · Worked closely with stakeholders to incorporate feedback and improve features.
- Conduct code reviews and pair programming
- Identify areas of improvement and advocate for best practices
- Architecting components based on the story requirements

CONTRACT FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Lime Digital | July - Sep 2021

- Provided development services and testing of SaaS product using VueJS front-end framework.
- Implementation of real-time asynchronous data with Google Firebase.
- Refactored and optimised existing codebase and fixed bugs.
- Provided estimations for projects and functionality.

TECHNICAL COFOUNDER

KiwiQuads | 2017 - 2021

- Built internal tools for complex querying, analyzing, and visualizing of supplier and sales data for Ecommerce using javascript frameworks.
- Management of deployed internal web tools on AWS using serverless architecture, authentication, and SQL databases.
- Development and maintenance of a large-scale ecommerce website responsible for \$1M ARR and 20k+ monthly visitors.
- Development of custom ecommerce functionality with integrations to NZ Post and various payment providers.
- Created SEO campaign for ecommerce website.
- Website implementation of Google Analytics with Tag Manager and custom ecommerce events.
- Built remarketing automations with Facebook business manager, Google Ads, and Klaviyo using dynamically generated product data feeds.

SENIOR ELECTRONICS TECHNICIAN

Royal New Zealand Navy | 2017 - 2020

- Leadership role, managing team of Electronics Technicians and providing support to engineering command.
- SME (Subject-matter expert) for Navigation and Information Systems on Navy Patrol vessels.
- Investigated and tested new electronic systems and equipment.
- Responsible for forecasting and planning of technical system maintenance.

JUNIOR ELECTRONICS TECHNICIAN

Royal New Zealand Navy | 2012 - 2017

- Responsible for testing, maintaining and repairing electronic equipment.
- Ensured system readiness and uptime in unique working environments.
- Assisted Weapons Engineering staff with operations and maintenance.
- Provided system and equipment reports to senior engineering staff and command.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Strong understanding of web design conventions and best practices.
- · Experienced working with big data and complex databases.
- · Confident communicator and tech translator for non-technical staff.
- · Advanced CAD Modelling in Solidworks.
- Hardware progamming using Arduino and other microcontrollers.
- 3D Printing, rapid hardware prototyping.
- Talented article, tutorial, and technical document writer.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

CERTIFICATE IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING LEVEL 4

Achieved at RNZN Naval Academy in 2015

GOOGLE CERTIFICATIONS

- Advanced Google Analytics Certification
- Google Analytics for Power Users Certification

HOWICK COLLEGE

Graduated Class of 2011.

- Achieved NCEA Level 3, University Entrance
- Focus in Digital Design, Computers, and Mathematics